&gt；&gt；Speaker 1：如果您只对字符串使用const，这会是一种有用的方式吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: If you use just const for strings, would that be a helpful way to?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：是的，我只使用const关键字表示原语，不变的值。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Yes, I only use the const keyword for primitive, immutable values.
这适用于字符串、数字和布尔值。
So that goes for strings, numbers, and booleans.
即使这样，我也只在那个东西基本上是语义的时候才用它
And even then, I only use it when that thing is basically a semantic
占位符，我会把文字放在一个或几个地方。
placeholder for where I would have just put the literal in one or a few places.
所以我不会仅仅为了使用const而对每个字符串都使用它。
So I wouldn't just use it for every string just for the sake of using const.
但是如果我有一根绳子，我要把它粘在某个地方，比如
But if I had a string where I was gonna stick it somewhere, say for
例如API URL，嗯，这是一个完美的例子。
example an API URL, well, that's a perfect example.
您的API URL几乎肯定不会在整个运行时更改
Your API URL's almost certainly not gonna change throughout the runtime
程序的。
of the program.
在该作用域的顶部分配一次，将其命名为customerApiUrl，
Assign it once at the top of that scope, call it customerApiUrl,
然后在程序中使用该常量。
and then use that const in the program.
它为字符串文字赋予了语义意义。
It gives semantic meaning to otherwise that string literal.
&gt；&gt；扬声器1：然后对于数组和对象，我通常只是将深度冻结或
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: And then with arrays and objects I usually just put deep freeze or
在它周围定格。
freeze around it.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：所以是的，我确实喜欢使用object.Freeze，这是一个肤浅的
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So yes, I do like to use object.freeze, which is a shallow
数组或对象中所有属性的只读锁。
read-only lock of all the properties in an array or an object.
这表面上确实使它变成了一个不变的值。
And that does sort of ostensively make it into an immutable value.
不是很深，因为它不深，但它可以达到这个目的。
Not really, since it's not deep, but it sort of does that purpose.
尽管如此，我还是不会说const x=object.Freeze，因为它假装
Still, I won't say const x = object.freeze, because it pretends to
用户好像const与冻结有关，但它没有。
the user as if const has something to do with the freezing, and it doesn't.
所以我仍然只会将const与其中一个基本的不可变值一起使用。
So I still would only use the const with one of the primitive immutable values.